<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Member-rsses on Neu3CA</title>
    <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Member-rsses on Neu3CA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Neu3CA, 2016 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://neu3ca.github.io/member/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephan Heunis</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/stephan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/stephan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stephan studied mechatronics and biomedical engineering at Stellenbosch University in South Africa, obtaining his M.Sc. in 2012. He worked for 4 years in two industries (Industrial Automation and Enterprise Mobility) before acknowledging the gravity of his calling: becoming a neuroscientist. His broad interest lies in using our increasing grasp and control of technology to help us understand and educate each other on the comparatively unknown realm of the human brain. More specifically and currently, Stephan is working on finding a way to use real time feedback from fMRI brain scans towards treating cognitive impairments in epilepsy patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Baeken</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/chrisbaeken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/chrisbaeken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a psychiatrist, prof dr Chris Baekens main interests are within the neurobiological field of Affective Disorders. To gain more insight in the underlying mechanisms of emotional brain processes in the ‘healthy’ as well as in the ‘mentally affected’ human brain, brain-imaging paradigms (MRI, fMRI, (S)PET,….) are used with or without the combination of neuromodulation techniques, such as rTMS and tDCS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lisanne Canjels</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/lisannecanjels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/lisannecanjels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lisanne Canjels studied Biomedical Engineering at the Eindhoven University of Technology. During the master program, she went to Boston for a six-month internship at the MGH/HST Martinos Center for Biomedical Engineering in the PET-MRI lab headed by Dr. Catana. During her graduation project she collaborated with the UMC Utrecht. These projects triggered her interest in MRI research. In December 2016, she started a PhD project at the Radiology department of Maastricht UMC studying post-stroke epilepsy using high field (7T) MRI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlotte Germonpré</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/charlotte/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/charlotte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Short bio&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marijke Miatton</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/marijke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/marijke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2001, Marijke Miatton started her career as an assistant at the Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences at the Ghent University. In 2007 she fulfilled a PhD thesis on the topic “Neuropsychological functioning of children with a surgically corrected congenital heart defect” in collaboration with the Pediatric Department, Prof. D. De Wolf and Dr. K. François.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2008-2010 she worked as a post doctoral researcher at the Ghent University, Department of Internal Sciences. Since 2010, she is a full time psychologist at the Neurology Department of the Ghent University Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She combines clinical work with research activities and since the majority of patients were provided by the Neurology Department of the Ghent University Hospital, she started to focus on neuropsychological functioning in patients with epilepsy and neurodegenerative disorders. Together with the Reference Center for Refractory Epilepsy and the Laboratory for Clinical and Experimental Neurophysiology, Neurobiology and Neuropsychology (LCEN-3), we investigated the effects of deep brain stimulation on the neuropsychological functioning of patients with refractory epilepsy with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with Prof. Helmstaedter from the University Clinic of Bonn, Marijke was responsible for the neuropsychological part of the international collaboration between the universities of Gent, Bonn and Freiburg on the study “Controlled Randomized Stimulation versus Resection”, a prospective randomized controlled study of neurostimulation in the medial temporal lobe for patients with medically refractory medial temporal lobe epilepsy. Further, we have a good working collaboration with Prof. Dr. Aldenkamp and Dr. M. Hendriks of the Expertise Centrum Epilepsy, Sleep Disorders and Neurocognition from Kempenhaeghe, Heeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We further focus on the concordance of biomarkers and neuropsychological functioning in collaboration with Dr. A. Sieben en Dr. T. Van Langenhove neurologists with expertise in neurodegenerative disorders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marijke was also co-founder of Parkinson Zorgwijzer Vlaanderen, a initiative that strives for qualitatively better care for patients with Parkinson’s disease by providing specialized education to health care providers in Belgium. Marijke is a member of the Paramedic Board of the Belgian Stroke Council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last, she is a postdoctoral volunteer and is promoter of students for the faculties of Health Science, Medicine and Psychology in their scientific and clinical work on several neurological topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robrecht Raedt</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/robrecht/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/robrecht/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robrecht Raedt was born September 19, 1980 in Kortrijk (Belgium). He obtained his Masters degree in Biology at Ghent University (Belgium) in 2002. In 2007, he successfully completed his PhD research at the Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences of Ghent University. The topic of his PhD research was &amp;lsquo;Cell Therapy for Epilepsy&amp;rsquo;. This work implicated isolation and culture of stem cells, biochemical characterization of cell clones, cell grafting in various epilepsy models, immunohistochemistry, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He worked as a postdoc at the Laboratory for Clinical and Experimental Neurophysiology, Neurobiology and Neuropsychology at Ghent University (LCEN3) on unraveling the mechanism of action of neurostimulation therapies for epilepsy (vagus nerve stimulation and deep brain stimulation) both in animal models as in patients with epilepsy. This work involved techniques such as microdialysis and intracranial electrophysiology in rats and single-unit recording in humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since he was appointed as a Assistant Research Professor at Ghent University in 2011, Robrecht Raedt is doing research on the neural basis of behavioral control (cognitive and emotion control) using intracranial recording and neuromodulatory techniques during cognitive testing both in humans as in animal models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robrecht Raedt was also associated to the University of Lethbridge (Dr. McNaughton lab) from 2012 to 2014 to investigate the neural dynamics leading to the development of  spontaneous epileptic seizures using high density recordings in the hippocampus of rodent models for epilepsy. In addition, he is involved in modulation of neural circuitry using optogenetics and DREADD technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veerle de Herdt</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/veerle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/veerle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Short bio&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter H. N. de With</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/peter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peter H.N. de With (Fellow of IEEE) received his PhD degree from the University of Technology Delft, the Netherlands. In 1984-1997, he worked for Philips Research Eindhoven on video compression and chaired a cluster for programmable TV architectures as senior TV Systems Architect. In 1997-2000, he was full professor at the University of Mannheim, Germany, Computer Engineering, and chair of Digital Circuitry and Simulation. In 2000-2007, he was with LogicaCMG in Eindhoven as a principal consultant Technical SW and distinguished business consultant. He was also part-time professor at the TU/e, heading the chair on Video Coding and Architectures. In 2008-2010, he was VP Video (Analysis) Technology at Cyclomedia Technology. Since 2011, he has is full professor at Eindhoven University of Technology and appointed scientific director Care and Cure Technology and theme leader Smart Diagnosis and later Participatory Health in the TU/e Strategic Area Health program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has set up an image analysis program with multiple regional and national hospitals for forms of oncology detection analysis, of which esophageal cancer detection  projects became of breakthrough nature and of leading international quality.  He is also international expert in video surveillance for safety and security and has been involved in multiple EU projects on video analysis, object and behavior recognition, and in surveillance projects with the Harbor of Rotterdam, Dutch Defense, Bosch Security Systems, TKH-Security, etc. He is board member of DITSS and R&amp;amp;D advisor to multiple companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is Fellow of the IEEE, has (co-)authored over 300 papers on video coding, analysis, architectures, 3D processing and their realization. He is (co-) recipient of multiple papers awards of the IEEE CES, VCIP and Transactions papers and Eurasip award.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regina Luttge</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/regina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/regina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Luttge studied Applied Sciences in Germany (1989-1993). She had been working as an engineering researcher at Institut für Mikrotechnik in Mainz, Germany, for nearly 5 years prior to starting her PhD studies in Microsystems Technologies at Imperial College in 1999, London, UK. In 2003, Luttge was awarded a PhD from University of London on the development of fabrication technology for micro-optical scanners. Switching her research interest  to microfluidics applications, Luttge had been working for 12 years at University of Twente’s MESA+ Institute for Nanotechnology, The Netherlands, first as a senior scientist and since 2007 as an assistant professor prior to joining TU/e. Based on her established scientific profile in Nanoengineering for Medicine and Biology, Luttge has been appointed associate professor in the Microsystems Group at the Department of Mechanical Engineering in June 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is the head of the Brain-on-a-Chip project, which is part of the Organ-on-a-Chip program at the department of Mechanical Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rob Rouhl</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/robrouhl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/robrouhl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting from his appointment in 2012 as a neurologist in the Maastricht University Medical Center+, Rob Rouhl focussed on epilepsy. His research interests are the new diagnostic and therapeutic possibilities for patients with epilepsy. As such he is involved in the deep brain stimulation for epilepsy and epilepsy surgery program of the Academic Center for Epileptology, a cooperation between MUMC+ and Kempenhaeghe. His research in the diagnostic spectrum includes new techniques like whole exome sequencing and auto-antibody testing. In his clinical research line post-stroke epilepsy is one of the points of gravity. He is an active board member of the Dutch League against Epilepsy, and of the Scientific Section of this League.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wytse Wadman</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/wytse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/wytse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wytse Wadman studied experimental physics in Utrecht, Delft, and London, and has a PhD on human motor system control. After post-docs in München, Israel and the USA, he works since 1989 as a professor of Neuroscience at the University of Amsterdam. Since 2005, he is also guest professor at the Faculty of Medicine in Ghent. His research group performs fundamental research of brain processes related to learning and memory, and diseases such as epilpesy, schizophrenia and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. Besides that, computational models are being developed and collaborations with industrial partners are maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antoine Bernas</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/antoine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 11:45:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/antoine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Antoine Bernas studied Biomedical Technology at Institut Supérieur de l&amp;rsquo;Electronique et du Numerique and did a studies called &amp;ldquo;Génie Electrique&amp;rdquo; at Université de Sherbrooke (2008-2013). He then did a PDEng at TU/e in Healthcare System Design (HSD) and now is a PhD candidate in the field of MRI and brain dynamics at TU/e. Antoine likes to play the drums and has a magnificent French accent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anton Tijhuis</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/antontijhuis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 11:45:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/antontijhuis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anton G. Tijhuis received the M.Sc. degree in theoretical physics from Utrecht University in 1976 and the Ph.D. degree from the Delft University of Technology in 1987 (cum laude). From 1976&amp;ndash;1986 and 1986&amp;ndash;1993, he has been employed as an assistant and associate professor at the Laboratory of Electromagnetic Research, Faculty of Electrical Engineering, Delft University of Technology. In 1993, he was appointed full professor of Electromagnetics at the Faculty of Electrical Engineering of the Eindhoven University of Technology. He has been a visiting scientist at the Universities of Boulder, Colorado (U.S.A.), Granada (Spain) and Tel Aviv (Israel), and with McDonnell Douglas Research Laboratories, St. Louis, Missouri (U.S.A.). Since 1996, he is a consultant with the T.N.O. Physics and Electronics Laboratory, the Hague, the Netherlands. His research interests are the analytical, numerical and physical aspects of the theory of electromagnetic waves. In particular, he is working on efficient techniques for the computational modeling of electromagnetic fields and their application to detection and synthesis problems from several areas of Electrical Engineering. This includes work on the modeling of Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anton de Louw</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/antondelouw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 11:45:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/antondelouw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Anton de Louw is a neurologist at Kempenhaeghe and is the medical director of the Academic Centre for Epileptology (ACE), which is a cooperation between Kempenhaeghe and Maastricht UMC. He is also involved in clinical research, mainly on the topic of the transition of children with epilepsy to adulthood. More recently the elderly patient with epilepsy is in his field of interest. Anton has a research affiliation at TU/e. Furthermore, Anton is the chair of the Dutch League against Epilepsy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bert Aldenkamp</title>
      <link>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 11:45:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neu3ca.github.io/member/bert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Professor Aldenkamp graduated in Groningen and was appointed Professor In Leiden in 1991 and in Amsterdam in 1998. Currently he holds the Chair of Epileptology and Neurocognition of Maastricht University Medical Centre (department of Neurology) and is Head of the Epilepsy Imaging Research Group of the Research School Mental Health and Neurosciences (MHeNS) of the University of Maastricht. In addition he is the Head of the Department of Behavioural Research of the Epilepsy centre Kempenhaeghe and vice-chairman of the Scientific Unit of the institute as well as member of the Strategic Board and the Central Management Team. He is currently the supervisor of 20 PhD students and finished more than 100 PhD studies. In addition: Visiting Professor of Epileptology, Universital Hospital Gent (Department of Neurology). Professor Aldenkamp is the Past Editor-in-Chief of the European Journal of Epileptology since 2012 and member of the Editorial Boards of medical journals such as: Epilepsy and Behaviour, Acta Neurologica Scandinavica and Clinical Neurology and neurosurgery. Member of the International Advisory Board of two Pharmaceutical companies. Member of the Dutch advisory Board for two pharmaceutical industries. Professor Aldenkamp has published more than 300 publications (including chapters) and gave about 500 international presentations (h-factor: 51). Since March 2013 he is appointed Professor at the University of Technology in Eindhoven faculty of Electrical Engineering, Signal Processing System group. He focusses on Brain MR-imaging and detailed processing of MR signals especially to understand processes of neurodegeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>